unitusccu.com 2010-11-30

# Privacy Policy :: Unitus Community Credit Union

**Privacy Pledge:** At Unitus Community Credit Union we respect the privacy of our members. We recognize the importance of maintaining the confidentiality of your personal financial information. We want to protect the personal and financial information that you have entrusted to us. Therefore, we have developed the following privacy policy and approach that respects and addresses your needs. We believe that all personal and financial information specific to you that you provide to the Credit Union through any channel constitutes personal information. The notice describes the privacy policy and practices followed by Unitus Community Credit Union.

**Information We Collect:** The Credit Union collects only relevant information about members that is needed to establish and maintain your account and services as the law allows or requires us to collect. We may collect personal and financial information about you which is “nonpublic.” The member information we collect varies depending on the accounts and services you request and use. We collect information about you from the following sources:

  * Application Information  
We retain personal information we receive from you on any application you provide to us or our affiliate for membership, deposit accounts, EFT services, loans, insurance, or other Credit Union services. This information includes: name, address, email address, social security number, birth date, phone number, employment and financial status, and credit history.
  * Your Transactions  
Any time you make a transaction on one of your accounts, including ATM or card transactions, loan advances, transactions through online banking, over the phone or at a branch we retain the transaction information, including: your account number, the date, amount, location of the transaction, and other pertinent information. Our affiliates or partners may also provide us with reports on your transactions with them.
  * Credit Reports  
When we evaluate your application for an account or service, we may request a credit report from a consumer-reporting agency. We retain the personal and credit history information and may use it to evaluate your eligibility for additional services.
  * Online  
We may obtain information you provide online when you visit our website, www.unitusccu.com. This includes retaining information you provide us on any online applications, online banking transaction or information you send to us by email.

**Information We Share:** All financial companies need to share member’s personal information to run their everyday business – to process transactions, maintain member accounts, and report to credit bureaus. In this section, we discuss the types of information we share and the types of companies with whom we share member information. Information we may have about former members is only shared or disclosed if necessary to enforce or administer an account or as required by law. 

  * Sharing Information with Third Party Service Providers  
In order for us to conduct our operations, including servicing your account or processing your transactions, we need to share information with our service providers, including: data processing companies, check, ATM and other payment processing companies, payment networks, insurance companies, collection agencies and credit reporting agencies, with whom we have contractual agreements. These service providers act on our behalf and have agreed in writing to keep the member information we provide to them confidential. We share the following categories of information to third party service providers depending on the specific services provided: 
    * Personal information (name, address and account number);
    * Account information (type of accounts, account balances, and transaction history);
    * Transaction information (dates, amounts, locations, and type of transaction).
  * Sharing Information with Other Financial Service Providers  
To ensure you have access to quality financial services, we will occasionally assist nonaffiliated financial service providers (i.e., insurance companies) to offer their products or services to our membership as part of a joint marketing agreement. We carefully screen these companies, looking for companies who share our core values, along with a desire to provide quality, low-cost financial services. When we do assist in offering you financial products provided by other financial service providers, we have contractual control of your member information used to make such offers. The Credit Union does not and will not sell or provide personal information to third parties for independent use or to telemarketing firms.
  * Sharing Information with our Affiliates  
At this time the Credit Union does not share member information with any affiliates. If in the future the Credit Union decides to share member information with one or more affiliates, you will be provided with a revised Privacy Policy and will be given reasonable opportunity to opt-out prior to your information being shared.
  * Sharing Information as Legally Required or Permitted  
We may share any member information of yours in response to a lawful request issued by a court, government agency, or regulatory authority or as permitted by law in order to administer or enforce your account. We may also share our experience information about you with credit bureaus. Our reporting to credit bureaus is governed by the Fair Credit Reporting Act, which affords you the right to make sure that your credit bureau reports are accurate.
  * Our Confidentiality and Security Safeguards  
We maintain strict policies and security controls to assure that member information in our computer systems and files is protected. Our employees are permitted access to member information that they may need to perform their jobs and to provide service to you. Our employees have access to such member information as necessary to conduct a transaction or respond to your inquiries. All employees are trained to respect member privacy. No one except our employees has regular access to the Credit Union computer system and records storage. The Credit Union has established internal security controls, including physical, electronic and procedural safeguards to protect the information you provide us and the information we collect about you. We will continue to review our internal security controls to safeguard your member information as we employ new technology in the future.

**Honoring Your Preferences:** You have choices when it comes to how Unitus shares and uses your information.

If you are a Unitus member or joint owner of a Unitus account, you may request that we not share information about accounts with other financial service providers described above by contacting us at 503-227-5571 or 1-800-452-0900. If you request that we do not share information with other financial service providers, we may still share information where permitted or required by law, or with our third party service providers to maintain our relationship with you, or as necessary to enforce or administer your account.

If you have multiple accounts with us, you may need to express your preference for each account separately. When any owner of a joint account requests that we do not share with third parties, we apply that preference to the entire account.

**Privacy on the Internet:** Unitus Community Credit Union uses a cryptographic (digital certificate) key to secure account information sent between our server and your browser. Whenever you use uOnLine, Unitus’ server responds to your transmission by sending this key that is authenticated by your browser. This communication key encrypts the data sent by you and Unitus Community Credit Union decrypts it when we receive it. Unitus uses firewalls that are designed to protect your accounts from unauthorized access from outside the Credit Union. 

**Protecting Your Children’s Information Privacy:** The online financial services offered through Unitus Community Credit Union’s website are not designed for or directed toward children under the age of 13. We do not knowingly solicit or collect data from children, and we do not knowingly market to children online without express parental consent or notification. If we receive online information from any child we will only use the information to respond directly to a child’s request. We recognize that protecting children’s identities and online privacy is important and that responsibility rests with us and with parents. If you believe your child has provided personally identifiable information to us, please contact us so we can allow you the opportunity to review and delete such information.

**What Members Can Do To Help:** Protect your account numbers, card numbers, PINs (personal identification numbers), and passwords. In particular, never keep your PIN with your debit card or credit card, as that makes you vulnerable in the event you lose your card or your card is stolen. Use caution in revealing your account numbers, social security numbers, etc., to other persons. In particular, if a caller tells you he/she is calling you on behalf of the Credit Union and asks for your account number, you should beware. Legitimate Credit Union staff would already have access to that information. It is important that the Credit Union has current information about how to reach you. If we detect potentially fraudulent use of your account, we will attempt to contact you immediately. If your address or phone number changes, please let us know.

**Privacy Policy Inquiries:** We reserve the right to amend this Privacy Policy at anytime and will notify you as required by law. If you have any questions about our privacy practices, please contact us.

**PLEASE CONTACT US AT:**
